<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">TechUpdates</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment" translatable="false">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="itsec_headline" translatable="false">New form of universal quantum computers</string>
    <string name="machinery_headline" translatable="false">MIT develops reconfigurable antenna for Advanced Satellite Communications Testing</string>
    <string name="itsec_content" translatable="false">"Quantum computing is a field that refers to solving complex problems using the laws of quantum mechanics. As vast development is taking place we require machines that have less response time but they prove to work efficiently. Quantum computers can be useful in various fields such as Artificial Intelligence(AI), Cryptography, Molecular modeling, weather forecasting, Particle physics, etc. Quantum computers can solve such problems that a traditional computer cannot. Considering the current state, the computing power of quantum machines is very low. It is very challenging for physicists to increase their power. But now they have presented a new architecture for overcoming these limitations. This universal quantum computer could be the basis of the next generation of quantum computers. Traditionally, in a quantum computer quantum bits also known as qubits act as a computing unit as well as memory at the same time. Generally, it is not possible to copy quantum information, and cannot be stored in a memory as followed in a classical computer. Due to this drawback in quantum computers, all qubits must be able to interact with each other. Achieving this is quite challenging. In 2015, theoretical physicists Wolfgang Lechner, Philipp Hauke, and Peter Zoller considered this situation and proposed a new architecture for a quantum computer. It is now named LHZ architecture. The name is significant as it is named after the physicists of this research. Wolfgang Lechner of the Department of Theoretical Physics at the University of Innsbruck, Austria said, This architecture was originally designed for optimization problems. In the process, we reduced the architecture to a minimum in order to solve these optimization problems as efficiently as possible. The physical qubits in this architecture do not represent individual bits but encode the relative coordination between the bits. This means that not all qubits have to interact with each other anymore. Physicists have now proven that the parity concept is also suitable for universal quantum computers. Parity computers can basically perform operations between two or more qubits by using a single qubit. They have shown that parity computers can perform quantum Fourier transformations. It is basically a building block of many quantum algorithms. Thus, this requires fewer computation steps along with less response time. Michael Fellner from Wolfgang Lechner's team explains,  Existing quantum computers already implement such operations very well on a small scale. However, as the number of qubits increases, it becomes more and more complex to implement these gate operations. However, as the number of qubits increases, it becomes more and more complex to implement these gate operations. Generally, quantum systems are more prone to disturbances. Quantum computers must correct these errors continuously. Anette Messinger and Kilian Ender, members of the Innsbruck research team said, Our model operates with a two-stage error correction, one type of error (bit flip error or phase error) is prevented by the hardware used. The other type of error can be detected and corrected via the software. Thus, this will create a way for the next generation of universal quantum computers to be realized with manageable effort. "</string>
    <string name="machinery_content" translatable="false">We are aware of the role of signals transmitted over the internet. From making television visible to security applications, it has come a long way. Each new day brings up a new development in discrete fields. Such a technological development has come across in the field of satellite communication.
MIT(Massachusetts Institute of Technology) has developed a reconfigurable antenna. This antenna can transmit and receive signals over multiple radio-frequency bands. This antenna is relevant to military and commercial applications.
Features of this reconfigurable satellite are:
It is a 38-foot-wide dome-shaped radio antenna.
It has a climate-controlled environment with a steel structure that supports a 20-foot diameter.
It is a 20,000-pound SATCOM antenna.
It can rotate 15 degrees per second by completing a single revolution in 24 seconds.
It can detect and track satellites in medium and low Earth orbit.
This antenna is called Multi-Band Test Terminal(MBTT). Before the installation of MBTT, the laboratory was dependent on various smaller antennas such as OTAKaTT(Over-the-Air-Ka-band Test Terminal ). Compared to OTAKaTT, MBTT is seven times more sensitive. It is specially designed to ease the reconfiguration for supporting multiple radio frequency(RF).
Brain Wolf,  a technical staff member in Lincoln Laboratorys Advanced Satcom Systems and Operation Group said, "As a much larger, more powerful, and more flexible test asset than OTAKaTT, the MBTT is a game-changer for enabling the development of advanced SATCOM technology.
MBTT was designed for supporting four commonly used bands for satellite communication: X, Ku, Ka, and Q. These bands span frequencies from 7GHz to 46 GHz. However, MBTT can prove to be supportive to even other bands in near future. This can be achieved through the design of additional antenna feeds, the element connecting the antenna to the RF transmitter and receiver.
With the view of switching between the various RF bands, MBTT must be configured with a new antenna feed in such a way that it emits signals onto and collects the signals from the antenna dish, and RF processing components. When it is not in operation, the MBTT command center stores antenna feeds and other RF components.
The feeds come with variations in sizes. The largest is six feet in length and weighs nearly 200 pounds. The feed and all the RF processing components such as the high-power amplifier and the downconverter needs to be replaced. Before running any tests, technicians must rectify the new feed for ensuring its proper operation.
MBTT has supported a wide range of tests including PTW. PTW is a waveform for providing highly secure and jamming-resistant communications. The laboratory used its PTW modem prototype as the terminal modem to conduct an over-the-air test with the Inmarsat-5 satellite. In 2020, the laboratory used the MBTT for demonstrating PTW at X-band over SkyNet 5C. SkyNet 5C is a military communications satellite that provides services to the British armed forces and coalition North Atlantic Treaty Organization forces.
“It’s an exciting time to be involved in this effort, as vendors are developing real SATCOM systems based on the concepts, prototypes, and architectures we’ve developed,” says Wolf.
MBTT also supported non-PTW testing. Technicians there have tested new signal processing technology for suppressing or removing jammers, new techniques for signal detection, and new methods for connecting PtW users to other departments of Defense systems.
</string>
    <string name="startup_headline" translatable="false">New development of wireless,  battery-free, underwater camera</string>
    <string name="startup_content" translatable="false">Engineers have built a battery-free, wireless, underwater camera.
It has always been fascinating for everyone to learn about the underwater world. But studying the same has been a very critical task for researchers. According to the estimation, more than 95 percent of Earths oceans have never been observed. The high cost and requirement of power had made it very challenging for underwater observations. But now the researchers at MIT have taken a huge step toward this by developing a wireless, battery-free underwater camera that is 10,000 times more efficient than other underwater cameras. It can also capture images in dark underwater areas.
This particular camera is powered by sound. It converts mechanical energy into electrical energy that powers its imaging and communication parts. It uses sound waves to transfer data to a receiver. It doesnt require any power source, it can run for weeks. It can also be used for monitoring overall ocean pollution by capturing images.
The camera can run continuously for many weeks even with no power supply. This would enable researchers to study more about unexplored regions and carry out discoveries.
According to the researchers, one of the most exciting applications of this camera is that it can also be used for climate monitoring. It could help in building more accurate climate models and understanding how climate change affects the underwater world.
This camera acquires energy through transducers. These transducers are made from piezoelectric materials that are placed on the exterior. They produce an electric signal when a mechanical force is applied to them. Whenever a sound wave traveling through the water hits the transducers, they convert mechanical energy into electrical energy.
When the camera captures an image, a red LED shines and then uses image sensors to take the photo. This same is the procedure with green and blue LEDs. Even though at this stage the image looks black and white but at the post-processing stage the image can be reconstructed.
Once the image data is captured it is encoded as bits. Then one bit is sent to a receiver at a time using the process called underwater backscatter.
The researchers have tested this camera under various water conditions. They have also captured many images as such of African Starfish. They have successfully transmitted data that is 40 meters range away from the receiver.
This is a great innovation in terms of research in the underwater world.
</string>
    <string name="business_headline" translatable="false">Music class in sync with higher math scores</string>
    <string name="business_content" translatable="false">Music is an art that has proven to be a therapy for many mental health problems. Even music therapy is widely accepted by many people. It has proven its advantages in curing diseases such as depression, autism, Alzheimers disease, etc.
As humans, we are always curious to learn new art forms. Being consistent in learning new art forms helps us to stay busy, achieving different growth at a personal level. It changes our mindset and helps us in developing a positive attitude.
It is also essential for educational institutes to include art classes along with the regular curriculum in the timetable. These classes will help students in the following ways:
It will help them to increase their knowledge about art.
It will allow them to showcase their creativity.
It will help them to gain self-confidence.
According to the new study, including art and music classes in school has proven to be beneficial for students in increasing their scores in mathematics.
Learning music is definitely co-related with improving math skills. At some level, music is also math. Music deals with time signatures, beats per minute, and formulaic progressions. Performing this, thus reinforces parts of the brain while doing math.
In this study, the researchers used a large nationally representative dataset for observing which types of art classes impact math achievement and the variation in results due to the socio-economic status of schools. The researchers found that taking music courses relates to higher math scores w.r.t. higher-or-mid-SES schools.
Daniel Mackin Freeman, a doctoral candidate in sociology, and Dara Shifrer, an associate professor of sociology said, " That's not a surprise given the ways in which music and math overlap. If you think about it at an intuitive level, reading music is just doing math. Of course, it's a different type of math but it might be a more engaging form of math for students than learning calculus".
However, the positive relation between music and math depends upon the SES of schools. According to the researchers, it is so because the quality of music courses provided in lower-SES schools is low compared to the quality of music courses in higher-SES schools. Also, it is observed that the students in lower SES take lower music classes as the awareness related to the importance of this is not known to them.
Mackin Freeman said," It'd be reasonable to expect that at under-resourced schools, the quality of the music program would differentiate any potential connection to other subjects. For programs as resource-intensive as something like band, under-resourced schools are less likely to even have working instruments, let alone an instructor who can teach students to read music in a way that they can make connections to arithmetic".
Further, he said, "Creating an environment where students have access to a well-rounded curriculum might indirectly affect math achievement. That could be something as simple as, they're willing to go to class because they have band or painting class to look forward to".
This study has added to the importance of music in human life.
</string>

</resources>